# Saiyeda Maham Shamail

Maham's Linked In Maham's GitHub

I'm a front-end developer with 1 year of professional experience. However, I have been programming since the past 5 years which has helped me develop exceptional problem solving skills. I have worked with major technologies like React Native, Android, iOS, Django and can learn new technologies/languages very quickly.

## **Work Experience**

#### Software Developer Intern

#### iMerciv

June 2020-Sep 2020

**Location Services Team** 

Toronto, Canada

- Developed mobile app's front-end technologies using React Native and Redux.
- Improved GPS accuracy tests by collaborating on Python scripts.
- Integrated Map-box location visualisation platform on the front-end.
- Connected to APIs and routing servers to send and receive JSON data.

#### **Python Developer**

#### **Cheetal Technologies**

Oct 2019-Dec 2019

Karachi, Pakistan

- Developed web app front-end technologies using **Django** framework.
- Provided web development support for clients in manufacturing industries.
- Implemented 70% of the data visualization dashboard for production lines using Django Python framework.

#### Web Development Intern

#### **Research Center for AI - Scube Incubation**

**Summer 2018** 

Karachi, Pakistan

- Developed Wordpress Websites.
- Used SEO principles to help improve site ranking on google search.
- Researched sponsorship opportunities for AI based agriculture projects.

#### **Education and Certifications**

- Post Graduate Certificate. Mobile Application Development and Strategy, Georgebrown College, Toronto.
  2020–2021
- **B.Sc. Computer Science,** Institute of Business Administration, Karachi.

2015-2019

# **Technologies and Languages**

Javascript ES6 | HTML 5 | CSS3 | React.js | Redux | React Native | Python 3 | Django | SQL | Git | SQL | C/C++| Java | Android | Swift | iOS | Figma | Adobe Photoshop | Content Writing | Microsoft Office | UX Design | Wordpress

### **Projects**

- **Portfolio Website:** I am in the process of updating my portfolio website using CSS, HTML and Javascript. You can find the source code on <a href="GitHub">GitHub</a>.
- Tourism Android and iOS Apps: As part of my academics I developed iOS and Android apps.
- **React Native Project** This Mobile App follows the user GPS location and displays their live coordinates on the screen. You can find the source code here.